Tony Gama

SENIOR FULL STACK DEVELOPER

ACHIEVEMENTS

- 1. Developed a large scale MERN Full Stack Application using React, Node.js, Express.js and MongoDB.
- 2. Upgraded an Existing Application's Frontend by 30%
- 3. Integrated 3 External APIs into an Application
- 4. Reduced Development Time of New Features by 50%
- 5. Launched 5 Projects Utilizing Different Tech Stacks

EXPERIENCE

MERN FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

Apr 2022 – PRESENT Plego Technologies

- Engineered robust and scalable architecture for web applications using Node.js, Express, React, Redux and MongoDB achieved 50% increase in user engagement and reduced server response time by 30% through effective implementation of caching and database optimization techniques
- Developed integration with 3rd-party APIs such as DocuSign and Zoho for document collaborative work.
- Worked on automation tools such as an auto-assignment feature that allowed users to create rules that triggered the automatic filling out of form fields when creating contracts.
- Successfully migrated an application to the cloud, resulting in a 50% reduction in hosting costs.
- Developed a new component in React that was used to define complex conditions based on field values, used throughout the application in many features.
- Oversaw the creation of coding standards and started a discussion about code quality management in the company.

Technologies: Node.js, Express.js, Nest.js, React, Vue, SCSS, Agile, SQL, Zoho API, CSS, Typescript, JavaScript, C#, Git, HTML5, .NET Core, C#.NET, APIs, Front-end, Full-stack, Architecture, REST APIs, Best Practices, Object-oriented Programming (OOP), Software Design Patterns

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

Apr 2021 – Apr 2022 Tempora

- Used Node.js, and React.js to write robust APIs and components that scale
- Worked on creating tools that set up the supply pipeline—finding builders with the skills that clients needed.
- Worked on the pipeline efficiency to process files with thousands of lines efficiently and asynchronously, using microservices and 3rd-party services.

CONTACT

tonygmstar@gmail.com (713) 955-7635 www.linkedin.com/in/tonygama-fullstack Houston, TX

ABOUT ME

A full-stack web developer who started with MERN as his chosen tech stack and, more recently, worked mainly with C# and Python. Proficient in React, Vue and Angular. Am a quick learner, willing and able to learn new skills rapidly, and is experienced in working in a multinational environment. Have cooperated with teams and clients from US and various European countries.

EDUCATION

St. Edward's University, 2018 Master's in Computer Science

University of Texas at Dallas, 2015 Bachelor's in Computer Science

- Developed a front-end internal tooling platform in React to give access to all the tools the team built to the other employees in the company.
- Migrated AngularJS SPA to React and Redux, improving performance significantly.
- Designed and developed key parts of an API gateway and nine microservices based on Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB and deployed in a Kubernetes cluster.
- Provided technical expertise and insights to direct troubleshooting efforts and solution development.

Technologies: Node, js, TypeScript, PHP, React, Angular, Express, js, Amazon Web Services (AWS), Kubernetes, CSS, JavaScript, Git, HTML5, Redux, Front-end, Full-stack, CI/CD Pipelines, Tailwind CSS, OAuth, Architecture, Redux Toolkit, PostgreSQL, REST APIs, Best Practices, Python, Object-oriented Programming (OOP), Software Design Patterns

SENIOR REACT, VUE, ANGULAR, AND NODE.JS DEVELOPER

May 2018 – Apr 2021 TekRevol

- Developed core features and dashboards for the merchant portal of Gyapu e-commerce marketplace using React with Redux and Styled Components on the front-end, while also implementing order processing and payment APIs using Node.js on the back-end, helping thousands of small businesses to efficiently manage product listings, orders and inventory on the platform.
- Developed and maintained both front-end and back end layer of Parts Source's platform using Express.js and React.
- Cooperated with the designers and back-end developers to ensure the proper quality of the provided solution.
- Implemented server-side rendering for the React application using Next.is.
- Developed the intake module using Node.js, GraphQL, and REST API.
- Provided UI expertise with Angular and React to troubleshoot existing UI problems and build new user-friendly forms—revamping the user experience.
- Reduced the size of the data access layer by 50%.
- Introduced automated E2E testing to facilitate regression testing for each push to QA.
- Maintained and developed a Microsft SQL database and an API in Node, is that utilized this database.
- Mentored the team and enforced Scrum principles, ensuring the Scrum process's quality.

Technologies: React, Mpde/ks, Vue, Angular, Redux, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, Git, Agile, HTML5, ASP.NET Web API, .NET Core, C#.NET, Front-end, Full-stack, CI/CD Pipelines, OAuth, REST APIs, Azure DevOps, Best Practices, Object-oriented Programming (OOP), Software Design Patterns

REACT DEVELOPER

Apr 2017 – May 2018 Screenlink Technologies

- Implemented the database logic and APIs to support a new pricing model for TotalJobs Recruiter Platform, the UK's largest job site. Built the front end in React.
- Refactored the existing code to use design patterns and best practices.
- Adapted 50+ clients' websites to changing industry standards, designed application architecture on TypeScript, React, and Redux, accelerating development rates by 15%.
- Created and enforced coding standards which ensured the quality of solutions developed by the team.

SKILLS

Languages

TypeScript, CSS, HTML5, JavaScript, C#, HTML, C#.NET, SQL, SCSS, Python, PHP

Frameworks

Node.js, Express.js, Nest.js, .NET, .NET Core, ASP.NET Web API, Entity, Swagger, Angular, ADO.NET, Redux, Next.js, Tailwind CSS, ASP.NET Core, Windows Communication Framework (WCF), ASP.NET MVC, ASP.NET MVC 5, Knockout (Knockout.js), Windows Presentation Foundation (WPF), ASP.NET

Libraries/APIs

React, Vue, Vue 2, Node.js, React, REST APIs, jQuery, AutoMapper, Zoho API, Entity Framework, Web API 2

Tools

Git, Bitbucket, Jenkins, TeamCity, Azure DevOps Services, Jira, Visual Studio, Gulp, RabbitMQ

Paradigms

Agile, Scrum, REST, Best Practices, Object-oriented Programming (OOP), FluentValidation, Azure DevOps

Platforms

Visual Studio Code (VS Code), Software Design Patterns, Amazon Web Services (AWS), Azure, Windows, Kubernetes

Other

MVC Frameworks, WCF Web Services, GitFlow, APIs, Front-end, Front-end Development, Full-stack, CI/CD Pipelines, Episerver, Cloud, User Interface (UI), OAuth, Architecture, Redux Toolkit, Octopus Deploy

Storage

MSSQLCE, PostgreSQL, Microsoft SQL Server, IBM Db2 - Ensured the high quality of the development solution by proposing and implementing code quality enhancements.

Technologies: React, Typescript, Redux, jQuery, JavaScript, Git, Agile, Scrum, HTML5, CI/CD Pipelines, OAuth, REST APIs, Best Practices, Object-oriented Programming (OOP), Software Design Patterns

ASSOCIATE DEVELOPER

Aug 2016 – Apr 2017 Screenlink Technologies

- Maintained and conducted workshops for a desktop application facilitating the financial reporting process.
- Developed multiple web apps used for gathering financial data from users.
- Contributed to the statutory financial audit as an auditor, gaining knowledge about accounting processes.
- Learned how to write performant and robust business logic using Node.js and REST API
- Worked with a systems engineer to gain an understanding of network security and maintainable infrastructure, including AWS.

Technologies: jQuery, Node.js, Windows Communication Framework (WCF), Windows Presentation Foundation (WPF), CSS, .NET, JavaScript, C#, HTML5, C#.NET, Front-end, Full-stack, REST APIs, Object-oriented Programming (OOP)

CERTIFICATIONS

SEPTEMBER 2020 - PRESENT

Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate Web Applications Microsoft

AUGUST 2018 - AUGUST 2013

Microsoft Certified Solutions Developer Web Applications Microsoft

JULY 2018 - PRESENT

Microsoft Specialist: Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3 Microsoft

MARCH 2016 - MARCH 2018

Developing and Implementing Windowsbased Applications with Microsoft Visual Basic .NET and Microsoft Visual Studio .NET Microsoft